JOHNATAN WRIGHT

Google Cloud Platform certified DevOps Engineer

+1-854-831-1367 • larry.liang@gmail.com • github.io/larry.liang • Richmond, VA

Summary

Spent 10 years developing the skills to increase velocity, reliability, and quality with a high focus on security. Deep experience with Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Kubernetes, and helping organizations instill DevOps for the modern age.

Education

University of Richmond

Richmond, VA 2006 - 2010

B.S. Computer Science | GPA: 3.85 / 4.0

Experience

Billed Richmond, VA

DevOps Engineer 2018 - Present

Billed is an American software company that develops financial and tax preparation software and related services for small businesses, accountants and individuals.

- Managed a Chef environment with 250 roles, 400 cookbooks, and 3,000 nodes
- Completed data automation project 3 months ahead of schedule and \$80K under budget for our manufacturing sites in China
- Maintaining 24 hours operations, and ensuring 99.9% uptime for the servers, performing backups of all servers
- Implemented Dockers to enhance developer productivity by 30% and server consolidation and Management by 20%

Richmond, VA Lessard **DevOps Engineer** 2013 - 2018

Lessard is a software development outsourcing company, delivering products ranging from web and mobile applications to complex backend solutions, mainly for the US market.

- Dramatically reduced development overhead by removing over 50,000 lines of deprecated code from the baseline of a \$1.2M project
- Automated software and infrastructure deployments for over 32 software projects across 4 lines of business
- Maintained and optimized a 40-node Elasticsearch cluster that collects 1 billion documents daily
- Ensure availability of Production and Development systems based on Google Cloud Platform EC2 and EKS

Richmond, VA Carroll 2009 - 2013

Software Engineer with Java

Carroll specializes in building and maintaining websites for enterprises. Their portfolio spans over 300 different websites.

- · Developed PHP applications with seamlessly integrated applications and databases in a very power and cost-efficient manner
- Administered, designed and developed an SQL relational database model across 10 databases to facilitate efficient data manipulation and data consistency
- Created a fast, real-time flight search tool using Pathfinders FlightStats API for AffordableFlights.com

SKILLS

Programming Skills: JavaScript · Java · Bash · PHP

Databases & Cloud services: MySQL · PostgreSQL · MongoDB · Redis · Oracle WebLogic · GCP

Tools: Packer · Docker · Kubernetes · Ansible · Puppet

Development: TDD · CI/CD · Incremental Releases · Pipelines · Agile · Jenkins · Chef

Strengths

Communication Open-minded, outgoing and patient

in conversations with others.

Flexability/Organisational skills

Managed to finish over 8 full-scale courses while working full-time to earn my GCP DevOps Engineer certification.

> CV Enhancy Powered by